

SOFTWARE ENGINEE

Tokyo,Japan

□ (+81) 70-4416-5273 | ▼rishantagarwal+jobs@gmail.com | ♠ www.rishantagarwal.com | □ rishantagarwal

| in rishantagarwal

Profile Summary _____

Computer Science graduate, working as full stack developer for 5 years with focus on Frontend technologies, to provide better, device independent, responsive experience to the user. Making the best use of the Agile development and Testing. Attending seminars, online courses, tech meetups and follow blogs by the core developer & team members to keep my knowledge up to date with the latest technologies.

Experience _____

Cogent Labs

Daikanyama,Tokyo

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Feb. 2018 - Present

- Developing Web Apps using React JS for AI system (OCR and NLP system)
- Worked with Redux, React-router, Redux-persist and other latest JS Libraries
- Backend development in Node JS, developing API's
- Testing using Jest, Cypress and CI using Jenkins and Drone
- Experienced with using GA and Sentry Integration
- Experienced with Package bundling and size optimization
- Website performance analysis with Webpage Test API, Lighthouse, Webpack bundle analyzer
- Container Orchestration using Kubernetes on GCP, familiar with Docker

Nijibox (Recruit Ventures)

Ginza.Tokvo

FRONTEND ENGINEER

Jan. 2017 - Dec. 2017

- Developing Web App using React JS Framework for startup Knowbe.jp
- Worked with Redux, React-router, Redux-persist and other latest JS Libraries
- Testing using Jest and Cl using Jenkins
- Currently authoring a Video course on Webpack
- Also worked with GA, Sentry, ELK Stack
- Website performance analysis with Webpage Test API, Lighthouse, Webpack bundle analyzer

Hikari Tsushin Tokyo, Japan

SOFTWARE ENGINEER & TECHNICAL LEADER

Nov.2014 - Dec.2016

- Developed a Salesman Customer Appointment Management System using FuelPHP,MySQL,Redis,HTML,CSS,JS,ReactJS,Jquery.
- Attendance System using PHP, MySQL.
- Hybrid iOS App for Sales purpose using AngularJS,Ionic,Cordova.
- API Server using NodeJS, Express, JWT.
- JAVA Web App Development & Maintenance
- Project Management System using Salesforce, Jquery, Visualforce, Apex
- Automated project deployment system using Jenkins, SVN, ShellScript

Zomato Gurugram,India

WEB DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Sept. 2014 - Oct. 2014

- Algorithm design & development for Data classification in PHP
- Data visualization tools development using D3.Js

Blue Jeans Networks

Bangalore, India

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

Jan. 2014 - July. 2014

- Developed testing code using Selenium API's, Java and JavaScript
- Researched and Improved existing code base.
- Won Blue Jeans Networks annual Hackathon. Developed a Voice Conferencing system.

Other Projects _____

Academic Projects

- Developed a File Management System using MongoDB,PHP,JS and HTML
- Developed a Web Portal to conduct an Online Hacking contest for Educational purpose. Application was used by more than 500 people at peak time. Developed using PHP,MySQL,JS
- Developed an Intelligent Healthcare System. Deployed on Google App Engine, it used for Twillio SMS Api's for communicating and was based on NLP
- Developed a Timetable generator system using Genetic Algorithms
- Developed a Compiler for a self developed Toy Language.

Hobby Projects

- Developed an Anonymous E-mailing server using Google Cloud Engine Mailing API's.
- Developed a collaborative sketching application using Node JS and Socket IO. Multiple users can draw together on the same canvas.

Open Source Contributions

- Middleware for Sentry and Redux
- Contributed to Joomla! Test Code
- Contributed to Webpack Documentation
- Developed and released a Cordova Plugin for Geolocation Tracking

Achievements _____

2010	IIT-JEE, Got 7277 Rank out of 0.5 Million Students	<i>Top 1.5%</i>
2010	AIEEE, Got 9580 out of 1.1 Million Students	Top 0.8%
2013	InCTF 2013, InCTF CTF Hacking Competition Finals	Finalist
2014	Blue Jeans Networks, Won Hackathon at BJN	Winner
2014	Oracle Certified, Java Programmer	
2014	GAIT Certified , IT Professional	Tokyo,Japan

Skill Set _____

- Comprehensive Knowledge of HTML, CSS, JS, HTML5 and CSS3
- Experienced With React JS Framework
- Proficient with developing and consuming API's.
- Proficient with developing Platform independent Applications.
- Familiar with Developing Hybrid Mobile Apps for iOS.
- Web Application testing manually and automated.
- Familiar with graph DB like Neo4j and NoSQL.
- Proficient with working with MySQL DB.
- Proficient with CI tools like Jenkins and Automation.

Programming Languages, JS,NodeJS,PHP,Java,C,VisualForce,Apex

Database, MySQL,Redis,MongoDB

Operating Systems, Ubuntu, Windows, MacOS

Languages, English, Hindi & Japanese

Tools & Technologies, GIT,SVN,Jenkins,Bitbucket,JIRA,Gherkin,Cucumber,ShellScripting

Education _____

BITS(Birla Institute of Technology & Science), Pilani

Pilani, India

2010 - 2014

 ${\sf M.Sc.}({\sf Tech})\ {\sf Information}\ {\sf Systems}$

• Elected as President, Computer Society.

• Monitored all IT activites on campus for an year, handling a team of 50 people.

Central Board of Secondary Education

India

BISHOP CONRAD SCHOOL 2007 - 2009

- Scored 90% in Class XII with major in Physics, Chemistry, Maths & Computers
- Scored 87% in Class X